ANUJ VERMA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detailed oriented and self motivated software professional with over 10 years experience in analysis, design and development.

Passionate for result-oriented approach with a focus on quality and user experience.

Product design, architect and leading development with focus on tracking, AB testing, SEO and AdOPs are some of the areas of expertise.

WORK HISTORY

<u>dubizzle, OLX Group</u> - Dubai, UAE Senior Software Engineer (October 2016 - Till Date)

- Managing UI Component library based on atomic design principles.
- Ground up setup for CI/CD for all the frontend apps including packages in monorepo for efficient development and release cycles.
- Developed on a Content-First approach for home pages, chat platform integration and payment module are some notable achievements.
- Actively managing SEO and AdOps.

CDK Global - Pune, India

Senior Software Engineer (Mar 2014 - October 2016)

- Worked with teams to build central IAM with oAuth.
- Developed chat service implementation with mongooselM.
- Led the development team for developing soft phone desktop apps with chat.

Entrib Technologies - Pune, India Senior Software Engineer (June 2012 - Feb 2014)

- Completed design concepts for consumer and enterprise apps.
- Led HTML5 Mobile apps development.

<u>Infosys</u> - Pune, India Software Engineer (Sept 2008 - June 2012)

- Developed a Set-top box application for monitoring viewers' viewing habits and helps delivering targeted ads to them.
- T9 dictionary implementation for TV Remote.

EDUCATION

B.Tech Computer Science and Engineering

Uttar Pradesh Technical University 2004-2008

REFERENCES

references available on request

CONTACT

Phone: +971-5225453595

Email: anujverma000@gmail.com

Blog: anujverma.netlify.com

Github: github.com/anujverma000

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/anujverma000

SKILLS

NodeJs, Express, NextJs
GraphQL, MongoDB
React, Redux, Redux Toolkit
React Native, ElectronJS
Javascript, ES6, JQuery
CSS, SASS, Styled Components
HTML, Pug, Handlebars
Webpack, Rollup, Grunt, Gulp
Docker, Microservices,
AWS, Serverless
Python, Java, Shell
CI & CD
Atomic Design
SEO and AdOps

SOFT SKILLS

Communication and Collaboration Leadership Business Analytics Product Management Agile and Scrum Master

PROJECTS

shopworx.io nextplane.net federationexchange.com

LANGUAGES

English Hindi